# ALLISON VON BORSTEL General Resume (708) 717-1937 | allison.vonborstel@gmail.com

Analytically minded, creative individual who is confident managing relationships and project development. 10+ years experience translating various technical jargon and communicating it to different stakeholders. Driven by results and dynamic teams.

#### SELECTED EXPERIENCE

### **SENIOR ECONOMIC MODELER** | Nielsen

Feb 2020 - Present

- Consult with multi-million dollar media companies to explain the impact of analytical decisions and how to best spend marketing budget to increase viewership
- Advise non-technical stakeholders how to define their technical needs using Nielsen tools
- Communicate proactively between data engineering and economic modeling team to anticipate issues threatening strict timeline for deliverables
- Create economic models that forecast how digital marketing budgets should be spent

## **RESEARCHER** | University of Chicago

Jan 2019 – Jan 2021

- Managed multiple research projects across the political science department
- Analytically determined the influence of Trump on congressional members and democracy through analysis of Twitter and Facebook
- Responsible for creating images and figures in an upcoming political science textbook

#### **POLICY CONSULTANT** | Cambridge Global Advisors

May 2018 – Aug 2018

- Identified and contracted governmental officials to participate in election hacking education
- Drafted media advisories and managed media coverage database with 1.3 million marketing
- Translated technical jargon between white-hat hackers for government officials

#### **GOVERNMENT CONSULTANT** | Project on Political Reform

Oct 2017- June 2019

- Directed research team and communicated timeline with all stakeholders
- Created database to determine the importance of name rotation on ballots
- Partnered with non-profits to identify strategic opportunities for executive orders

#### **POLICY AND DEBATE INSTRUCTOR** | Consolidated District 230

May 2015 – July 2017

- Taught 120+ students research, critical thinking skills, and how to fine-tune speaking skills
- Coordinated and managed debate workshop across the state of Illinois with 30 schools

#### **RELEVANT SKILLSETS**

- Direct and punctual communicator
- Conscious and intentional organizer
- Strong performance in high pressure environments
- Analytic competencies: R/SAS/SPSS/python/excel/QGIS

#### **EDUCATION**

MASTER OF PUBLIC POLICY | University of Chicago

**VISITING STUDENT** | University of Oxford

BACHELOR OF ARTS IN ECONOMICS AND INTERNATIONAL POLITICAL ECONOMY | Carthage College

INTERESTS: Competitive Debate (coach 10+ years) | "Hamilton" | Climbing fake rocks